Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements, Pre-55 Group, 1894-1957
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Container List
  - Toilet Goods
    - Beauty Specialists and Beauty Preparations
      - Botany Lanolin, 1943
      - Caron, 1933
      - Chanel, 1942
      - Charles on the Ritz, 1927-1930
      - Cheramy, 1928-1941, (3 folders)
      - Colgates, 1927
      - Creme Nerol, 1920
      - Coty, 1939-1953, (3 folders) (Box 194)
      - Covermark, 1938
      - Daggett & Ramsdell, 1935-1936, (2 folders)
      - Denton's Facial Magnesia, 1929-1930
      - Francis Denny, 1943
      - Dermetics, 1941
      - Djer Kiss, 1928-1931, (3 folders)
      - Domino House, 1922
      - Carolyn Drew, 1933
      - DuBerry, 1941-1944
      - Dumas, 1932
      - Duart, 1935-1936
      - Marie Earle, 1928-1941, (3 folders)
      - Early American, 1939-1952, (13 folders)
      - Elmo, 1941
      - Embassy, 1934
      - Frederics, 1928-1934, (7 folders)
      - Frigidine, 1927-1929, (2 folders)
      - Barbara Gould, 1930-1950, (9 folders)
      - Dorothy Gray, 1948
      - Harper Method, 1928-1934, (2 folders)
      - Hinds, 1930-1932, (3 folders)
      - Edna Wallace Hopper, 1950 (Box 195)
      - Houbigant, 1926-1947, (12 folders)
      - Richard Hudnut (including DuBarry Success School), 1931-1951, (8 folders)
      - Jergens, 1950
      - Jonteel, 1933
      - Kissproof, 1930
      - Krank, 1930-1931
      - Lady Esther, 1931-1950, (7 folders)
      - Lavena, 1936
      - Lentheric, 1934-1939
      - Lucien Lelong, 1940-1941, (2 folders)
      - R. Louis, 1928-1933
      - Lucille Young, 1929
      - Mme Bertie, 1930-1931
      - Madame Vaquet, 1931-1932
      - Manuel, 1928-1931
      - Marinello, 1925-1931
      - Marly, 1931
      - Mavis, 1928
      - Max Factor, 1931-1953, (18 folders) (Box 196)
      - Melba, 1929
      - Mercolized Wax Cream, 1933-1950, (8 folders)
      - Mineralava, 1923-1924
      - Milk Bath, 1936
      - Miner's, 1940-1942, (2 folders)
      - Mitcham Lavender, 1933
      - Germaine Monteil, 1942
      - Nestle (English), 1927-1935, (3 folders)
      - Pond's, 1943
      - Prince Matchabelli, 1935
      - Princess Pat, 1928-1942, (5 folders)
      - Printemps, 1934
      - Proker, 1934
      - Revlon, 1944-1953, (3 folders)
      - Revlon, 1946-1952, (6 folders) (Box 197)
      - Roger and Gallet, 1940
      - Rose Laird, 1934
      - Helena Rubenstein, 1927-1951, (18 folders)
      - Scandia Jourde, 1930-1931 (Box 198)
      - J. Schaeffer, 1928-1931, (3 folders)
      - Sempre Giovine, 1912-1925
      - Seventeen, 1930-1933
      - Tangee, 1927-1940, (6 folders)
      - Terra Derma Lax, 1922-1923
      - Tone, 1941
      - Tussy, 1944-1953, (9 folders)
      - Lucretia Vanderbilt, 1928-1929
      - Westmore, 1943
      - Woodbury, 1931-1942, (6 folders)
      - Yardley, 1943
    - Rouge
      - Carrot Rouge, 1925
      - Djer Kiss, 1920-1925
      - Richard Hudnut (including DuBarry Success School), 1954
      - Jarnac, 1925
      - Jonteel, 1920
      - Mad Cap, 1922-1923
      - Pert, 1925-1926
      - Po-Go, 1925-1938
      - Princess Pat, 1922-1940, (2 folders)
      - Pum-kin, 1926-1927
      - Rouge Incarnat, 1929-1930
      - Helena Rubenstein, 1922
      - Tangee, 1924-1927
      - Tre-Jur, 1924-1925
      - White Rouge, 1928-1930
      - Miscellaneous, 1920-1922
    - Beauty Specialists and Beauty Preparations, 1924-1939, (8 folders) (Box 199)
    - Eye Preparations--Maybelline, 1947-1949, (3 folders)
    - Sanitary Pads
      - Meds, 1940-1953, (9 folders) (Box 200)
      - Modess (Johnson & Johnson), 1927-1942, (13 folders)
      - San-Nap-Pak, 1943-1953, (11 folders)
      - Tampax, 1946-1953, (8 folders)
      - Curity, 1943 (Box 201)
      - Delnaps, 1920-1934, (5 folders)
      - Feminix, 1925
      - Fibs, 1943-1952, (10 folders)
      - Kotex, 1943-1953, (10 folders)
      - Parapad, 1924
      - Swanfleece, 1928
      - Venus, 1932-1942
      - Veldoun, 1929-1931, (2 folders) (Box 202)
      - Wix, 1937-1938
      - Holly-Pax, 1938-1942
      - Miscellaneous, 1924-1954, (14 folders)
      - Beltx, 1929-1930
      - Faultless, 1928
    - Shaving Preparations
      - Miscellaneous (Razors), 1954
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1954, (3 folders)
    - Shaving Cream
      - Miscellaneous, 1918-1928, (2 folders)
      - Barbasol, 1922-1939, (11 folders)
      - Burma-Shave, 1947-1951, (2 folders)
      - Colgates, 1948-1953, (2 folders)
      - Colgates, 1935-1946, (5 folders) (Box 203)
      - Bauer and Black, 1919-1921
      - Brisk, 1929-1930
      - Coty, 1931
  - Toilet Goods
    - Soap (toilet)
      - Ivory, 1926-1942
      - Jap Rose, 1928-1930, (3 folders)
      - Kirkman, 1937-1945, (5 folders)
      - Kirk's, 1927-1934, (6 folders)
      - Lanchere, 1928-1930, (2 folders)
      - Lana Oil, 1925
      - Larkin, 1922
      - Lifebuoy, 1939-1952, (4 folders)
      - Murphy's Oil (for house), 1931
      - Octagon, 1928-1932, (2 folders)
      - Olva, 1925-1928
      - Palmolive, 1925-1933, (2 folders)
      - Pall Mall, 1933-1935, (2 folders)
      - Pears, 1920-1937
      - Peets Crystal White, 1919 (Box 204)
      - Pine Tree, 1931
      - Plantol, 1925
      - Resinol, 1922-1927, (2 folders)
      - Roger Gallet, 1933-1935, (2 folders)
      - Swan, 1941
      - Sweetheart, 1928-1948, (11 folders)
    - Institutional
      - Proctor & Gamble, 1949-1952, (3 folders)
    - Soap (toilet)
      - Tag, 1939 (Box 205)
      - Woodbury, 1950-1954, (5 folders)
      - Wrisley's, 1944-1951, (7 folders)
      - Yardley, 1941
      - Zanol, 1929
      - Miscellaneous, 1934-1954, (15 folders)
    - Water Softeners
      - Climaline, Oaklite, etc., 1953
    - Dentrifices
      - Pepsodent, 1927-1936, (5 folders) (Box 206)
      - Squibb, 1925-1947, (5 folders)
      - Squibb, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 207)
      - Stera-kleen, 1935-1942, (5 folders)
      - Strasska's, 1930
      - Teel, 1939-1949, (9 folders)
      - Vivomint, 1920-1921
      - Worcester, 1933-1938, (2 folders)
      - Williams, 1927
      - Miscellaneous, 1943-1952, (12 folders)
    - Hair Preparations
      - Brownatone, 1943-1946
      - Conti Castile, 1927-1951, (16 folders) (Box 208)
      - Coty, 1933-1934
      - Cleero, 1925
      - Helene Curtis, 1951-1953, (3 folders)
      - Danderine, 1920-1952, (10 folders)
      - Drene, 1946-1950, (4 folders)
      - Dr. Dick's, 1928-1931
      - Duart, 1935-1937
      - Edens Wave, 1933
      - Eugene, 1932-1934
      - Fitch's, 1935-1953, (17 folders) (Box 209)
      - Ferond's, 1920
      - Farr's, 1930-1932, (7 folders)
      - Grayban, 1932-1933
      - Glo Co, 1929-1934
      - Glorilox, 1925
      - Glostora, 1927-1943, (2 folders)
      - Glover's, 1928-1953, (21 folders)
      - Godefry's, 1932-1933, (2 folders)
      - Golden Glint, 1927-1941, (5 folders)
      - Liquid Hair Groom, 1930
      - Miscellaneous, 1928-1930, (3 folders)
      - Mary T. Goldman's, 1931-1949, (15 folders) (Box 210)
      - Gray's, 1938
      - Halo, 1939-1952, (10 folders)
      - Kolor Bak, 1927-1933, (2 folders)
      - Harper Method, 1936
      - Richard Hudnut, 1948
      - Henna Tint, Henne Linine, Henalea, Hennafoam, 1921-1926
      - Hennafoam, 1929-1942
      - Brownatone, 1927-1941, (3 folders)
      - Brylcreem, 1939
      - Canute, 1937-1942, (3 folders) (Box 211)
      - Caroco, 1923-1924
      - Chamberlain, 1934
      - Brylcreem, 1938
      - Icilma, 1928
      - Jane Curran, 1930
      - Jeris, 1944-1948, (2 folders)
      - Jo Cur, 1939
      - Kep, 1941
      - Kreml, 1927-1953, (8 folders)
      - Inecto Rapid Notox, 1935-1940, (4 folders)
      - Lemon Rinse, 1927-1931
      - Laco, 1928-1953, (7 folders)
      - LaVay, 1930
      - La Geradine, 1932-1935, (2 folders)
      - Liquid Arvon, 1927-1933
      - Lorraine, 1924
      - Lovalon, 1937-1953, (8 folders)
      - Lustre-Crème, 1950-1953
      - Marcelle/Brilliantine de France, 1924-1928, (2 folders)
      - Marchand's, 1944-1953, (10 folders)
      - Marlene's Hair Waving Shampoo, 1952
      - Clairol, 1948-1949
      - Vitalis, 1928-1934, (5 folders) (Box 212)
      - White Rain, 1953
      - Miscellaneous, 1918-1944, (8 folders)
      - Dreme, 1947
      - Clairol, 1947
      - Coffelt's, 1937
      - Miscellaneous, 1948-1955, (11 folders) (Box 213)
      - Articles on hair, 1924-1928 (Box 214)
      - Miscellaneous, 1920-1953, (7 folders)
      - Permanents, Waves, 1954
      - Hair curlers, 1935
      - Hair pins, nets, etc., 1927-1934, (3 folders)
      - Hair dryers, 1927-1928
  - Automobiles--Trucks
    - Autocar, 1946-1953, (6 folders)
    - Chrysler, 1946-1953, (6 folders)
    - Diamond T, 1945-1953, (8 folders) (Box 215)
    - Dodge, 1945-1953, (9 folders)
    - Federal, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
    - General Motors--Chevrolet, 1951-1953, (3 folders)
    - International Harvester, 1953
    - International Harvester, 1947-1952, (6 folders) (Box 216)
    - Mack, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
    - REO, 1948-1952, (4 folders)
    - Studebaker, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
    - White, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1954, (8 folders)
    - Accessories/Parts
      - Antifreeze, 1950-1954, (5 folders)
      - Antifreeze, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 217)
      - Bearings, 1948-1954, (7 folders)
      - Chains, 1948-1954, (5 folders)
      - Express transportation, 1949-1954, (5 folders)
      - Spark plugs
        - A-C, 1949-1953, (5 folders)
        - Autolite, 1949-1953, (5 folders)
        - Champion, 1949-1953, (5 folders)
        - Miscellaneous, 1948-1954